Guide to the George Washington University, Office of Student Life records, 1915-2014 RG0115
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University, Office of Student Life records
1915-2004
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of Student Life
RG0115
87.5 Linear Feet
Collection includes Sigma XI membership nominations, meeting minutes, constitution and by-laws, annual reports, and history of Sigma Xi; student activities rosters and regulations, guides to student organizations, student telephone directory, publications, photocopies of news clippings of GW Band, button, posters, academic evaluations.
Restrictions on Access
Series 20 and 23 are closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Materials acquired through transfers from Office of Student Life.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Student life office is now a part of Student and Academic Support Services (SASS).
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include Sigma XI membership nominations, meeting minutes, constitution and by-laws, annual reports, and history of Sigma Xi; student activities rosters and regulations, guides to student organizations, student telephone directory, debate team trophies, publications, photocopies of news clippings of GW Band, button, posters, academic evaluations. The collection covers the years 1915 to 2004.
Collection Organization
Organized into 32 series: Photographs, Posters, GW Blitz newspaper, Rock Creek magazine, Unfiltered newspaper, Office files, T-shirt, Student handbooks, Student telephone directory, Student telephone directory, Debate teama trophies, GW Journal newspaper, Ghost magazine, GW Forum magazine, GW Insider, Ex Nihilo magazine, Academic evaluations, Independence magazine, Connection newsletter, Sigma Xi records, Student activities, Sigma Xi records, Hillel, GW Band, Buttons, Posters, Sigma Xi banners, Phi Beta Kappa, Campus posters, Sigma Nu Delta Pi Chapter fraternity records, and two of Office files. Note: There are no series with numbers 11 or 25.
Photographs; Student activities; Directories; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Washington (D.C.); George Washington University; Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society; George Washington University. Student and Academic Support Services
- Photographs, ca.1990; RG0115 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of photos of student life activities (orientation, President Trachtenberg inaugural gala, etc.) The materials range in date from ca.1990.
  - Photo Album, 04/16/1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Photographs from Trachtenberg's inaugural gala and other photos
  - Photo Album, 1989 ca. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Student orientation and campus scenes
- Posters, 1995-1996; RG0115 Series 2; 1 Linear foot
  This series consists of three fine art campus life posters (175th anniversary year). The materials range in date from 1995-96.
- GW Blitz newspaper, 2001-2002; RG0115 Series 3; 1 Linear foot (Flat box 1)
  This series consists of the GW Blitz student newspaper. The materials range in date from 2001-02.
- Rock Creek magazine, 1971-1978; RG0115 Series 4; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of Rock Creek, The George Washington University arts and literary magazine. The materials range in date from 1971-78. The magazine became Wooden Teeth in 1978. Issues of Wooden Teeth are part of MS2334.
- Unfiltered newspaper, 1995-1997; RG0115 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet (Box SHARED Box 4)
  This series consists of Unfiltered, GW's progressive journal. The materials range in date from 1995-97. Formerly ACC#517
- Office files, RG0115 Series 6; 3 Linear feet
  This series consists of student affairs library books and office files. The materials have no attributable date range.
- T-shirt, 1998; RG0115 Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of a Professor's Gate t-shirt. The materials range in date from 1998.
- Student handbooks, 1920-2002; RG0115 Series 8; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 1)
  This series consists of student handbooks (with photocopies of those from 1921-1942). The materials range in date from 1920-2002.
  - Student Handbook, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student Handbook, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Student Handbook, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    2 copies
  - Student Handbook, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student Handbook, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Handbook, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Student Handbook, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Student Handbook, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Student Handbook, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Student Handbook, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Handbook, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Handbook, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Handbook, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student Handbook, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Student Handbook, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Student Handbook, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Student Handbook, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Student Handbook, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Student Handbook, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Student Handbook, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Student Handbook for Women, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Consists of 3 parts
  - Student Handbook, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Student Handbook, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Map photocopy included
  - Student Handbook, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Student Handbook, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    GWU Handbook, 2 Student Activities leaflets
  - Student Handbook, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Student Handbook, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Student Handbook, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Student Handbook, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Student Handbook, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Student Handbook, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Student Handbook, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Engineers' Guide; 2 copies
  - Student Handbook, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Student Handbook, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Student Handbook, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Student Handbook, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Student Handbook, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Student Handbook, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Student Handbook, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Student Handbook, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Student Handbook, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Student Handbook, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Student Handbook, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student Handbook, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Student Handbook, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Student Handbook, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    3 copies
  - Student Handbook, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    2 copies; also includes Manual for Freshman
  - Student Handbook, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Student Handbook, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Where To Go Guide, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Also incudes Code of Conduct and Where to Go Guide
  - Student Handbook, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Student Handbook, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Also includes Code of Conduct and GWU Handbook
  - Student Handbook, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Student Handbook, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Student Handbook, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Student Handbook, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Student Handbook, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    2 copies; also includes Handbook for International Students
  - Student Handbook, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Student Handbook, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    2 copies; also includes Graduate School Hanbook
  - Student Handbook, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Student Handbook, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Student Handbook, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Student Handbook, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Student Handbook, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Student Handbook, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    2 copies; also includes Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Handbook
  - Student Handbooks, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    GWU Handbook; GWU Law Bulletin; Academic Guide for Entering Students
  - Student Handbooks, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Student Handbooks, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    GWU Handbooks (2 copies); Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Handbook; Handbook for International Students; Guide to Student Rights and Responsibilities
  - Student Handbooks, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    GWU Handbook; Graduate School of Arts and Sciences Handbook
  - Student Handbooks, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Student Handbooks, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    3 copies; titled The Planner; also includes Student Guide to the Library
  - Unofficial Student Guide, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Official Guide to the Gelman Library, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Guide to GW, 1999; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Guide to George Washington University, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Planner and Student Handbook, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Guide to GW, 2002; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Interactive Planner, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1921-1922 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1923-1924 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1925-1926 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1926-1927 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1928-1929 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1929-1930 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1930-1931 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1935-1936 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1939-1940 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Student Handbook (Photocopy), 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Student telephone directory, 1961-1996; RG0115 Series 9; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 3, Box 2, Box 1)
  This series consists of the student telephone directory. The materials range in date from 1961-96.
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Student Telephone Directory, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- GW Journal newspaper, 1999-2002; RG0115 Series 10; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of the GW Journal student newspaper focusing on campus life. The materials range in date from 1999-2002. Formerly ACC#994.
- Ghost magazine, 1921-1929; RG0115 Series 12; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of Ghost, a student satirical publication. The materials range in date from 1921-29.
  - GW Ghost, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Bound in black binding.
  - GW Ghost, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Folder contains 1921 issues and photocopy of related Washington Post article.
  - GW Ghost, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Bound in red binding.
  - GW Ghost, 03/1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Folder contains v.3:no.3 (March 1927). Formerly Acc#606
  - GW Ghost, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Bound in green binding.
  - GW Ghost, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Folder contains issues from 1928 and 1929.
- GW Folklife newsletter, 1982-1993; RG0115 Series 13; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of the GW Folklife newsletter, a publication of the GW Folklife Association. The materials range in date from 1982-93.
  Formerly Acc#410.
- GW Forum magazine, 1970-1999; RG0115 Series 14; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 1, Box 3)
  This series consists of GW Forum, a publication of the GW Faculty Senate. The materials range in date from 1970-99.
  Formerly Acc#411.
  - Bound magazine, 1969-1981 (Box 1)
  - Loose magazines, 1969-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1-11)
  - Loose magazines, 1982-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  - Loose magazines, 1991-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1-8)
- GW Insider, 1992-1996; RG0115 Series 15; 5 Linear feet (Flat box 5, Flat box 1, Flat box 2, Flat box 3, Flat box 4)
  This series consists of GW Insider magazine, which later became "It" magazine. The materials range in date from 1992-96.
- Ex Nihilo magazine, 1996; RG0115 Series 16; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of Ex Nihilo magazine, a University Honors program publication. The materials range in date from 1996.
- Academic evaluations, 1966-1996; RG0115 Series 17; 3 Linear feet (Box 5, Box 4, Box 2, Box 3, Box 1)
  This series consists of academic evaluations, which consisted of student evaluations of courses they took and the professors who taught them. The materials range in date from 1966-96.
  - Academic Evaluation, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - How to do Academic Evaluations, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Academic Evaluation (Spring), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Academic Evaluation (Spring), 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1981 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Academic Evaluation (Spring), 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Academic Evaluation (Spring), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Academic Evaluation (Spring), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Academic Evaluation, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Academic Evaluation (academic year), 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Academic Evaluation (Fall), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Academic Evaluation (Spring), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Academic Evaluation (academic year), 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Academic Evaluations (Fall), 1979 (Box 5, Binder 1)
    2 copies; binder
  - Binders: Academic Evaluations (Fall), 1979 (Box 5, Binder 2)
- Independence magazine, 1994-1998; RG0115 Series 18; 1 Linear foot (Flat box 1)
  This series consists of Independence magazine, which was formerly calleed "The Authority." The materials range in date from 1994-98.
  Formerly ACC#936.
- Connection newsletter, 1992-2000; RG0115 Series 19; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of Connection, a newsletter from Office of Parent Services. The materials range in date from 1992-2000.
  - Connection, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Vol.1:No. 1 (Fall)
  - Connection, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Vol.1:No. 2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Vol.1:No. 3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Vol.2:No. 1 (Fall)
  - Connection, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Vol.2:No. 2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Vol.2:No. 3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Vol.3:No. 1 (Fall)
  - Connection, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Vol.3:No.2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Vol.3:No.3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Vol.4:No. 1 (Fall)
  - Connection, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Vol.4:No. 2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Vol.4:No. 3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Vol.5:No. 1 (Fall)
  - GWU Family Weekend, 10/18/1996-10/20/1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Connection, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Vol.6:No. 1 (Fall)
  - Connection, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Vol.5:No.3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Vol.6:No. 2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Vol.6:No. 3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Vol.7:No.1 (Fall)
  - Family Weekend ' 98, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Connection, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Vol.7:No. 2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Vol.8:No.3 (Summer)
  - Connection, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Vol.8:No.1 (Fall)
  - GWU Family Weekend '99, 10/15/1999-10/17/1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Connection, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Vol.8:No. 2 (Spring)
  - Connection, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Connection, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Vol.9:No.1 (Fall-Winter)
- Sigma Xi records, 1935-1987; RG0115 Series 20; 6 Linear feet (Box 4, Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  This series consists of membership nominations, meeting minutes, constitution and by-laws, annual reports, membership lists, dues records, 50th anniversary programs and photos, manuals of procedures, history of Sigma Xi, annual meeting proceedings. The materials range in date from 1935-87.
- Student activities, 1915-1992; RG0115 Series 21; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series consists of student activities rosters and regulations, and guides to student organizations (including the GWU "Queue"). The materials range in date from 1915-92.
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1918 ca.-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1966-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student Activities Rosters and Regulations, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Trophies, approximately 1948-1990; RG0115 Series 22; 25 Linear Feet 20 record center cartons
  This series consists of debate team trophies. The materials range in date from 1948-90.
- Sigma Xi records, 1931-1981; RG0115 Series 23; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series consists of membership lists, meeting minutes, new member program booklets, pamphlets, constitution and by-laws, 50th anniversary, forms, manuals of procedures. The materials range in date from 1931-81.
- Hillel, 1949-2014; RG0115 Series 24; 7.5 Linear Feet (Box 9, Box 7, Box 6, Box 1, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3, Box 2)
  This collection contains records of the Hillel student organization including correspondence, publications, photographs, posters, fliers and administrative documents. The material dates from 1917-2014 with the bulk falling betwen 1949 and 2010.
  Arrangement
  Organized into 2 series: Original transfer and 2014 Transfer
  Biographical / Historical
  The mission of Hillel is to create a place to further the cultural, social and educational life of Jewish students on campus. Programs have always been diverse, ranging from the secular to the religious. Social activism and Zionism have been a vital part of Jewish campus life at George Washington University since the Menorah Society was established on November 26, 1915 as an organization of Jewish students who studied the ideals and cultures of the Jewish people. The Society's most important legacy was the formation of the Department of Semetics and the courese in Hebrew that soon followed.
  The Menorah Society cotinued until the mid-1930s and by that time anotehr Jewish organization had been established on campus. The Avukah Society, or simply Avukah, was the local branch of the Student Zionist Federation. It appears as though the group was formed in mind-1920s and lasted until 1930. Then Avukah reappeared in the mid-1930s and lasted until the 1941-1942 academic year, thus being the only Jewish organization on campus during that time. There is no record of a Jewish organization for a few years until the B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation began in 1946 with the assistance of the local Jewish community and the Hillel Councilship that had been launched two years prior in 1944. B'nai B'rith traditionally sponosored the Hillel Councilship and Hillel Foundation, however, that long relationship ended in 1995 when Hillel began the Foundation for Jewish Campus Life.
  The first three decades of Jewish campus actvity follwing the B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation's conception in 1946 was centered in an F street row house, affectionately called "Hillel House." The members remember it as dirty and cluttered, but nonetheless it was their haven. The biggest event onf Hille's first year was the Ball of Fire Dance that was open to the entire university. Among the highlights of the dance was the picking of the "Apollo" from all the male contestants. Its intitial success was so popular that it became an annual tradition until the early 1960xs. Religious observances, educational programs and social activities marked the years at the house on F street under the leadership of Rabbi Aaron B. Seidman (Director from 1951-1979). Rabbi Gerald Serotta became Director of Hillel in 1982 and it was under his leadership that Hillel finally recieved a much-needed permanent and more suitable home.